Italian Immigrant Women in New York City's Garment Industry Oral Histories, 1976-1978
Sophia Smith Collection
Italian Immigrant Women in New York City's Garment Industry Oral Histories
1976-1978
MS 556
1 box (.25 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Italian immigrants; Garment workers. Nine oral history interviews of Italian immigrants (primarily women) who worked in the U.S. garment industry from 1880 to 1950. Transcriptions and audio recordings.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
This oral history project was undertaken by Colomba Furio-Spigner as part of the research for her Ph.D. dissertation, "Immigrant Women and Industry: A Case Study: The Italian Immigrant Women and the Garment Industry, 1880-1950" (New York University, 1979). The collection consists of nine oral history interviews of Italian immigrants (primarily women) who worked in the U.S. garment industry from 1880 to 1950.
The following interviews consist of both audio recordings * and transcriptions (some transcriptions might be incomplete): Tina Gaeta, Antoinetta Lazarro, Grace Natarelli and Diana Romanik. Two interviews (Tina Cantania and Pauline Newman) have transcriptions only (these may be incomplete). The transcriptions were annotated by Jennifer Guglielmo of Smith College. Interviews of Mary Cacchione, Vincenza Crachhiolo, Ralph Iannantuono, Vanni Montana and Felicie Guiseppe Sagliano are audio only, no transcriptions. There are also summaries provided by Colomba Furio-Spigner of additional interviews with nine unidentified women.
[* Note: Audio recordings have been copied to CD for research use but sound quality is very poor due to deterioration of the original cassette tape. In some cases recordings are inaudible.]
The papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
Access to audiovisual materials may first require production of research copies.
This collection has not been fully processed and therefore may be difficult to use.
Additional Formats
Audio tapes have been copied to digital format CDs) for research use.
The oral histories were donated to the Sophia Smith Collection by Colomba Furio-Spigner in 2006.
Immigrants--United States--Biography--Sources; Italian American women--New York (N.Y.)--Biography--Sources; New York (N.Y.)--History--Sources; Labor--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Oral history--Archival resources; Women clothing workers--United States--History--Sources; Women immigrants--New York (N.Y.)--Biography--Sources; Cacchione, Mary; Cracchiolo, Vineenza; Furio, Colomba M.; Gaeta, Tina; Iannantuono, Ralph; Lazarro, Antoinetta; Montana, Vanni; Natarelli, Grace DeLouise; Romanik, Diana; Sagliano, Felicie Guiseppe; Colomba M. Furio. Immigrant women and industry: a case study, the Italian immigrant women and the garment industry, 1880-1950--Sources.
- SERIES I Interviews
  - Mary Cacchione and Vincenza Crachhiolo: audio recording and transcription (Box 1)
  - Tina Cantania: transcriptions only (Box 1)
  - Tina Gaeta, by Colomba Furio, Nov 22, 1976: audio recording and transcription (Box 1)
  - Ralph Iannantono: audio recording and transcription (Box 1)
  - Antoinetta Lazarro, by Colomba Furio, Mar 29, 1977: audio recording and transcription (Box 1)
  - Howard Molisani, by Colomba Furio, Feb 23, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Vanni Montana: audio recording and transcription (Box 1)
  - Grace De luise Natarelli, by Colomba Furio, Sep 22, 1978: audio recording and transcription (Box 1)
  - Pauline Newman, by Colomba Furio, Nov 17, 1976: transcriptions only (Box 1)
  - Diana Romanik, by Colomba Furio, Apr 1, 1977: audio recording and transcription (Box 1)
  - Felicie Guiseppe Sagliano: audio recording only (Box 1)